<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Boris Fazio</title>
    <link>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Boris Fazio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; I have no clue what my rights are yet.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bmfazio.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick peep into named distributions and 20th century statistical research</title>
      <link>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/a-quick-peep-into-named-distributions-and-20th-century-statistical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/a-quick-peep-into-named-distributions-and-20th-century-statistical-research/</guid>
      <description>This post is going to be about a niche lineage of papers I stumbled upon and my very opinionated take on it which, considering my current level of statistical knowledge, will in all probability be Quite Bad. First, an explanation for how I got there.
Some contextI’m currently doing my thesis on the endpoint-inflated binomial model. Building the actual model and fitting it under a Bayesian framework is pretty straightforward, but I’ve struggled a fair bit with finding practical use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great use case for flexdashboard</title>
      <link>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/great-use-case-for-flexdashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/great-use-case-for-flexdashboard/</guid>
      <description>Found this blog post by Jennifer Thompson today, thanks to the flurry of great content being shared on Twitter during #rstudioconf. It’s about making dashboards with the flexdashboard R package, with an application to monitoring clinical research.
I’m definitely going to be using this at some point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind obsession</title>
      <link>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/blind-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/blind-obsession/</guid>
      <description>Today I came across an excellent thread by Andrew Althouse on whether it makes sense to blind the Data and Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB) in a RCT (it doesn’t). The main reason is provided in this tweet:
“More evidence is required to stop a trial because of a benefit than because of harm. Trials are performed to assess safety and efficacy, not to “prove” harm…it is unreasonable to make the monitors behave as if they were indifferent to the direction of a treatment difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 is online</title>
      <link>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/2019-is-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bmfazio.github.io/post/2019-is-online/</guid>
      <description>I have been meaning to set up a personal blog for probably over a year now and I’ve finally found the time to do so. I probably could have done this a few months ago if I hadn’t spent so much time agonizing over choosing between Jekyll and Hugo, as well as finding the ideal theme.
Although some of that time was certainly spent on unnecessary nitpicking, I think it was worth it as I ultimately feel I made a comfortably informed choice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>